# Roberto Andrés Alvarado Moreira

Motivated programmer and researcher dedicated to the study of mathematics and its applications within computer science, passionate about the new technologies, artificial intelligence, optimization methods and numerical analysis. Searching opportunities to learn and delve deeper into the world of new technological research

raalvaradom@hotmail.com

**(+56)** 928588819

https://github.com/Robdres

Santiago, Chile

#### **Tools**

Python

#### Languages #

Spanish **English** 

### Programming Languages 💂

C++ MvSOL **JavaScript** Latex Java Rust 

#### **Developer Tools**

Vim Git Linux Perforce

# Frameworks y Libraries

#### C++

Curses Oare3D **JavaScript Angular Nodels** React **Python** TensorFlow Numpy

#### Skills

Leadership **Critical Thinking** Teamwork Communication

### **Certificates**

Huawei Technologies, Leadership in Engineering Bootcamp October,2022

# **Professional Experience**

# **R&D Junior Programmer**

June, 2023 - Present Santiago, Chile

In my current job as a research and development I was part of a group that manages and is in charge of chip verification. In just a few months, I learn enough to be left in charge of a complete tool in the process and I was able to create many tools to improve developer everyday work

## **Junior Programmer**

January, 2022 - February 2023

Tecsicom

Ouito, Ecuador

With a small group of programmers we were able to create a complete Angular based website for the daily operations of one of the biggest marketing companies

#### Researcher

June,2021 - May,2023

Universidad San Francisco de Quito

Ouito, Ecuador

Along with all my teammates in the artificial intelligence laboratory in the university, we have used neural networks to learn and create new applications for AI in our environment

# **Data Analyst Internship**

May,2023 - June,2023

Ney Torres Investment Fund

Quito, Ecuador

In charge to analyse and work with financial datasets to assess and improve stock trading analysis, in my short time I learned about the basics of trading enough to create a tool that makes a comparison analysis of financial metric

#### Teaching Assistant

lune.2022 - March.2023

Universidad San Francisco de Ouito

Quito, Ecuador

I helped and collaborated with David Hervas, Math PhD, with academic activities

### **Education**

# **Math Major**

January, 2019 - May, 2023

Universidad San Francisco de Quito

Quito, Ecuador

Courses: Numerical Analysis, Neural Networks, Differential Geometry, Real Analysis, Stochastic Processes

### **Computer Science Major**

January, 2020 - May, 2024

Universidad San Francisco de Quito

Quito, Ecuador

Courses: Artificial Intelligence, Databases, Computer Architecture, Java Programming, C++ Programming

### **Philosophy Minor**

January,2018 - May,2024

Universidad San Francisco de Quito

Quito, Ecuador

Courses: Philosophy of Religion, History of Philosophy, Process Philosophy, Platonic Dialogues

# **Projects**

#### **Testors**

August,2021 - May,2023

Universidad San Francisco de Quito

Learn and participate in many projects that involve the use of testors, also known as rough sets, in order to reach better processing times by reducing the number of attributes necessary for classification processes

#### **Palm Tree**

January,2023 - May,2023

Quito, Ecuador

Alongside professor Miguel Castillo from NC State University, it was possible to work with a database of the Palm Tree, to create metrics to analyse the performance of difference infrared measure devices.